A Guide to the Grinnan Family Papers, 1740-1935
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Small Bound Volumes
  - Memoranda Book: [Cornelia Grinnan] 1852 (Box 9)
  - Memoranda Book: [Helen Grinnan] ca. 1852 (Box 9)
  - Memoranda Book: [Andrew G. Grinnan] n.d. (Box 9)
  - Memoranda Book: A. G. Grinnan n.d. (Box 9)
  - Memoranda Book: [A. G. Grinnan] n.d. (Box 9)
  - Account Book: [Andrew Grinnan] with Stebbens, Mayan & Allen n.d. (Box 9)
- Manuscripts
  - Diary re: Spotwood Expedition (transcript) 1716 Aug-Sep (Box 9)
  - Diaries: [James M. Glassell] re trip to England and France 1825 Aug 16-1826 Jan 21, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Register: [Major James Glassell] n.d. (Box 9)
  - Poems n.d. (Box 9)
  - Religious meoranda left by Helen Grinnan ca. 1853 (Box 9)
  - Plats and surveys 1865, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Notebook re Dicas' Hydrometer n.d. (Box 9)
  - Notes re history and architecture n.d. (Box 9)
  - Notes re genealogy n.d. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes n.d. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous writings 1846, 1854, n.d. (Box 9)
- Printed Material
  - Broadsides and Circulars 1846-1895, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1855-1922, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material 1845-1874 (Box 9)
- Photographs and Memorabilia
  - Engraving of Chapman Johnson n.d. (Box 9)
  - Photographs of "Bush Hill" and Sam Pryor, a former slave 1898, 1908 (Box 9)
  - Memorabilia 1833-1907 (Box 9)
- Oversize Material
  - Land patent, to Francis Slaughter, 1200 acres in Orange County, signed by William Gooch, Lieutenant Governor of the Colony of Williamsburg 1734 Feb 27
  - Land grant, to Christian Willour, tract called "Christiana" in Milford township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania 1788 Oct 1
  - Account sales: Murray, Grinnan, & Mundell by George Murray & Co. 1801 Jun 2-1801 Sep 6
  - Account: John Mundell with Murray, Grinnan, & Mundell 1802 Sep 2-1803 May 31
  - Account: Murray, Grinnan, & Mundell with George Murray & Co. 1802 Oct 22-Dec 11
  - Bank account: [Murray, Grinnan, & Mundell] 1806 Sep 1
  - Land grant, to George Shull, tract called "Quebec" in Milford township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania 1809 Mar 18
  - ALS: F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] to John Coalter 1811 Jan 3
  - Account: George Murray with Murray, Grinnan, & Mundell 1811 Oct 1-1813 Mar 8
  - Indenture, Henry Seashols to Felix Beck, 47 acres in Antrim township, Franklin County, Pennsylvania 1815 Apr 1
  - Ledger: [Murray Grinnan, & Mundell] 1815
  - Indenture, John McCutchen to Peter Albright, 133 acres in Antrim township, Franklin County, Pennsylvania 1822 Nov 28
  - Deed poll, John M. Macay, sheriff of Franklin County, to John McCutchen, 133 acres in Antrim township with log house 1822 Nov 29
  - Certificate of religion, Kyoto, Japan. Printed in English and Japanese 1843
  - A Synopsis of Hardinge's Phonography ca. 1848
  - Indenture, Noah Shull, of Bensalem township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania, and Levi J. Shull of Pennsburg manor, Falls township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania, to Jeremiah Seashols and Peter Rotenberger of Kensington, County of Philadelphia, a wood lot of the "Galoway estate" in Bensalem township 1849
  - Land grant, Commonwealth of Virginia to Andrew G. Grinnan and Rufus K. Fitzhugh, 1717 acres in Madison and Page Counties, sighed by Henry O. Wise 1857 Apr 1
  - Mortgage, R. P. Lowe, W. W. Belknap, D. A. Day, J. P. Homish, and Calvin Coates to Edward Kilbourne, Keokuk, Iowa 1857 Aug 1
  - Land grant, for Cornelia Grinnan, sighed by James Buchanan 1860 May 1
  - Bond, State of North Carolina, unsigned 1863 Jan 1
  - Visa, Noah Shull 1867 May 23
  - Genealogy, Adams family of Brooklyn, New York ca. 1895
  - Survey, 108,000 acres in Giles, Craig, and Monroe Counties, Virginia n.d.